Anthony with Allen, just the cerebral
nature to him. What did you notice from
like a green dot standpoint and trying
to kind of project him mentally into
potentially doing that?
>> Yeah, high level communicator. Um, you
see that in person at practice, you see
that at a games and you see that on
film. Um, but yeah, highly instinctive.
I think he's got rare instincts for a
college football player. Um, so the
reactive quickness um, kind of allows
him to play faster. Um, and he's already
fast. You know, he ran ran really well a
couple weeks ago. Um but yeah, I just
see a rare field
um and for a two and a half year starter
in a complex system at Georgia and
there's a lot of on his plate mentally.
So, uh definitely I I could see green
dot potential for us and he's handled
that the last two years at Georgia.
>> How did you see him grow at Georgia?
Because I mean to start is a true
freshman in any capacity at school like
that probably speaks to how smart he is.
>> Yeah. Um I just think that is a tough
place to play in practice and man he
graduated from that program I like to
say. So, it's a hard thing to do. Um,
but yeah, I mean to come in there as a
freshman amongst all those really top
talent in the country and play early,
uh, I just think that speaks to his prep
out of high school and his
determination, just like his mental
makeup and maturity, man. Like, he's
just prepared, he's diligent, he's
detailed. Uh, he is the best practice
player I viewed this fall, I thought,
out of, you know, a few hundred players.
um just the intensity and focus he had
really stood out to me.
>> He's obviously a kind of a still I don't
know somewhat green in his position
transitioning from some different spots
on the roster over the years uh in his
time at at Florida. What what do you
make of what his potential is um and
maybe what's still kind of unscratched?
>> Yeah, I think there's a few things he
could clean up just technique-wise like
skill set, hand usage, foot usage,
having a plan as a rusher. He's only
been rushing for three years. He was a
walk-on receiver at Northern Illinois,
played some receiver, played some tight
end, uh, and then they they put him on
scholarship. Then he played DN for one
year, and that's kind of how Florida
found him. Um, but yeah, he's a little
green. I I wouldn't say he's like super
raw, though. Like there there's enough
there where there's a good baseline of
stuff for us to work with as far as his
skill set. Um, but man, you're seeing a
guy like he battled through some
injuries this year. Um, so the tape was
like solid. It was good. was a little up
and down sometimes just cuz he was
battling. Uh but man, you went to pro
day, it was excellent performance. I
thought movement athletically. Uh really
impressed me in person. Um and uh
obviously blew out the combine too with
his numbers. But you you see that on
film too.
>> How much when when a guy has the tools
like that, how much can that it doesn't
supersede the other stuff like the
technique issues, whatever, but like how
much can it make up for the lack in
other areas?
>> Yeah, I think you're just betting that
hey, this guy can figure it out. And
part of it is like, okay, he's got the
talent, he's got size, and then it's
like, does he have the football smarts
and the the drive to get better? Cuz you
can have potential, but like if you're
not going to work at it, it doesn't
matter. Um, and this is this guy's wired
the right way. Like super into football,
man. Like I just think it's a great
story, man. This guy, you know, like
this guy pursued football. He walked on
at a play at a max school and leveled up
and started at a SEC school and now
drafted to the NFL. So, he's got some
stuff to him where he's like really
determined and um I I'm really high on
the person. Um and I think he's very
talented as well.
>> Mike, with Holly going from a couple
different programs and ending at LSU,
what stood out to you about his journey?
And I mean, hearing all conference
honors at every stop.
>> For sure. I mean, it's going to sound
kind of similar to the C.J. Allen's
level of competitiveness, you know, this
kid, his drive, um, just his innate want
to to compete at a higher level, you
know, and just continue to do that and
produce and perform and, you know,
everywhere he goes, bet on himself and
earn a starting job and obviously, you
know, pick up some accolades along the
way. You know, very similar to, you
know, the guy Anthony just talked about.
>> Skill set wise, what stands out to you
about this game?
>> So, he's strong, right? He's got a
compact, muscular build, but I wouldn't
say, you know, don't let that fool you
because he's got a natural feel for
coverage, too. And he's quick. He can
change direction. Ran very well at the
combine, you know, so we feel good about
his long speed and range in the passing
game. Um, and again, I mean, he's not
scared to get his nose dirty in the run
game, and he's got uh ball production on
paper, you know, that tells you he can
take it away.
>> Were you guys surprised he was still
there? cuz he seems like physically and
athletically he seems like kind of one
of these modern safeties that never has
to leave the field. Like was it
surprising he would still be there?
>> I think I think uh you know depending on
who you ask people definitely thought
he'd go a little bit earlier but we felt
really good about you know him being
there for us and it was a no-brainer.
>> What do you think his experience helped
him? He he talked about, hey, I played
in a bunch of different, you know,
systems along the way and played, I
think, over 700 snaps last year. So,
>> yeah, a lot of snaps, a lot of exposure
to different schemes, different
terminology. Um, that speaks to his
football IQ, his ability to kind of get
to a new environment, a new school, new
program, and and pick it up like that,
you know, not, hey, you're going to be
the backup until you learn it. He hit
the ground running and knew what he was
doing. So, feel confident about his
ability to do that here with us. Chris
was talking about this draft class as a
whole having some competitive stamina to
it with Allen and Paulie maybe
specifically to start off like how do
those guys fit that that sort of
description?
>> Go ahead.
>> That that's a shoe win. I mean I I think
you know as as you guys speak to other
people who scouted everybody on this
list, the consistent theme is going to
be their their competitiveness, their
edge, the grit that they play with um
that we were talking about earlier, we
know for a fact we got tougher with this
year's draft. Mike Burks lasting as long
as he did. Um it seemed like pretty much
everywhere you looked they had him going
much much earlier than seven. Were you
pretty surprised he was still there?
>> Uh yeah. You know we were we tried to
figure it out amongst ourselves. You
know maybe why but you know either way
as as that you know we kept looking up
at that card. You know we felt good that
uh we were getting really good value for
where we took him in the draft.
>> Smaller fast guys like that kind of just
get thrown into the they're a slot or
they're a vertical guy. What about him
makes you think uh he could maybe be
more of a consistent maybe like an every
down type of [clears throat]
contributor, not just a niche player?
>> Sure. Yeah. Not not like your typical
size that you want out there, but I
think this kid pound-for-pound his play
strength and just how well put together
he is. I think he, you know, should not
be exclusively labeled a slot receiver.
You know, I think he has the speed to
kind of threaten vertically no matter
where you line him up on the field. And
then, you know, in some situations again
that that play strength, you know,
catches through contact or if he's
outside the numbers, I think, uh, you
know, he can do more than than just play
inside in my opinion.
>> Was that 26 pitch reps, was that legit
at the combine?
>> Very legit.
>> That's like very legit.
[laughter]
>> He is. Yeah, he's like I said, you know,
>> at his size, pound-for-pound, I mean,
this kid is very, very strong, very
explosive. You can feel it when he's
coming off the ball. Um and and again
you can feel it when he's running
through contact. I think that bench
press is consistent with what we kind of
saw on film. You
>> mind these guys five of these guys hit
the portal at some point in their
college career. Like how does that or
impact the scouting process? Is it
beneficial? Are there challenges that
come with it for both you guys?
>> Yeah, there's definitely [clears throat]
some challenges. Um I think you know
like last year I think we hit on Travis
because he kind of transferred up from
Princeton. uh gums transferred up you
would say uh to Hulsey you know going to
LSU um so I think that speaks to them
but yeah for our scouting process
there's there's a little more hurdles
when they bounce around just because if
you're at a place for one year how well
do they really know you um and I know
for a fact like all these guys we vetted
them at their their current school and
their previous school current position
coach previous position coach
coordinator coordinator so we do our due
diligence at both schools so it takes a
little longer longer to get all the
information, but we follow the same
process and steps. But that has uniquely
changed the past couple years with the
portal is like you're making a lot more
calls
>> um they may be a little shorter, but
you're calling more people um to get a
toz on them
[clears throat]
>> for for Burks. Um return-wise, do you
think he can offer something there?
>> Yeah, I mean, he's done it at Purdue.
He's been a kick returner there. Um, no
live game reps as a punt returner, but I
think the the toughness, the ability to
track it and field it, you know,
definitely things that he has in his
toolbox that suggest he'll be able to do
that for us, you know, might take some
take him a little bit of time to figure
it out because he hasn't done it live
yet. But, um, has done kicks and and
again, I think he's got the toughness,
the speed, um, the instincts, the
vision. I think he'll he'll be a guy
that, um, should be able to develop in
that department for us.